

PROFILE

Ploynarin is a senior consultant in Interactive Experience team at IBM. She began her career 3 years ago at IBM under Consulting by Degrees program. She is experienced in working with multinational teams from IBM across several areas which allows her to develop various skills both in sales and delivery. Her current focus is to use Experience Design and Strategy in driving business transformations specifically augmenting opportunities created by the digitally enhanced Service Design model.

CONTACTS



2529/10 Esta Home, Ratchadapisek Road, Bangklo, Bangkholaem, Bangkok 10120 Thailand



+668.1.441.9000



s.ploynarin@gmail.com

EDUCATION

The University of Melbourne, **Australia** 2009 - 2012

Bachelor of Commerce Majors: Marketing, Finance

Relevant studies: Marketing, Finance, Management, Economics, Quantitative Methods, Property Investment, Designing Environment

Huijia Beijing School, China 2007 - 2008 Higher School Certificate, **ACT Education**

EXTRA COURSE

- Design Thinking
- Essential UI/UX Patterns for Mobile Application Certificate

Ploynarin Suthileelakul

SENIOR CONSULTANT

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

IBM Thailand Company Limited

(Jul 2012 - present)

Digital Strategist

Dec 2015 - At present Worked as a digital strategist on one of the initiatives of the Digital Transformation program at a tier-I leading bank in Thailand. The role involved gathering business requirements, leading market research & survey activities, and planning & managing the agile project activities. The key milestone of this project is an ideation workshop where IBM team and stakeholders collaborate to understand the research findings, develop a long list of payment product ideas, prioritize the top ideas, and Identify the key principles and objectives that will drive the design of the Customer Journey Map. The ultimate objective of the project is to define a unique experience strategy for the bank to acquire and retain customers.

Conducted the pieliminary assessment of the client digital channels focusing on mobile to identify gaps between the current and desired states. Key industries include financial services, airlines, telcos, and hotels. Also worked with clients to validate the ideas and current paint points and come up with the roadmap for the proposal.

Business Development Manager

Jul 2014 - Aug 2015

Identified and worked to close business deals for a tier-1 leading bank in Thailand with an average of 35 million USD of total TCV managed and 25 of pipeline opportunities per annum. Responsible for gathering requirements, identifying issues, building solutions proposal, and preparing legal contracts. Worked with account partner and senior team to define and execute IT and business strategy for the client.

Business Analyst

Dec 2013 - Jun 2014

Worked for an integration project after the merger of two banks, and assisted in driving the overall integration program plan to completion. The role involved new business process requirement gathering, business process analysis to ensure flawless operation. The role also included project planning, project plan execution, organization change management, and fundamental financial analysis of a project to ensure that the integration is completed on time, within budget and to the highest level of quality. This project required conflict management, as there was language and cultural complexity as a result of a cross-border merger.

Innovation Program Manager

Aug 2013 - Nov 2013

Developed an innovation program, with the objective of strengthening client relationships and fostering collaboration across teams in one of IBM's largest clients. Encouraged the sharing and harvesting of innovative ideas and solutions, bolstered by the demonstration of pipof-of-concepts. Hundreds of ideas were submitted during the first quarter of the program, 10 of which were selected to turn into projects worth millions USD.

Deployment Communication Manager

Jun 2013 - Aug 2013

Worked with project director to enhance and develop communication plans to ensure corrective actions within the team and vendors of a large deployment project for a complex bank transformation. The communication and coordination skills were critical as the previous deployment was poorly managed. Throughout the project, I have maintained communication with all related stakeholders and ensured transparency throughout the team and this resulted in the most successful and effective deployment.

Project Management Officer

Worked in conjunction with the project director to improve the overall efficiency and performance of a team with over 50 employees. It was found that there was large skill gaps between business demand and existing resources. The role entailed activities including conducting skills assessment, identifying and eliminating skill gaps between business demand and current resources on the project by creating the right training programs and designing new recruitment procedures for the new team.

PwC Thailand

(Dec 2010 - Feb 2011)

Summer Associate: Sustainability Solutions

Developed and designed workshops for sustainability assessment for a leading Thai oil and gas corporate. Conducted research on the topic of sustainability practices in different industries relating to the client's operating business and to understand the nature of client's business, in order to provide the most applicable strategy for each client.

SKILLS

Business: Requirement Gathering and Analysis, Organization Change Management, High Level Functional Design, Operations Strategy, Business Deployment, Sales Process

Design: Design Thinking, Customer Journey Map, Persona, User Research, Prototyping, Wireframe, Agile Methodology, App Visual Design, User Experience Design

Basic: Client Presentations, Negotiation, Project Management, Relationship Management, Problem Solving, Teamwork, Leadership

Language: Thai, English, Mandarin (Basic), French (Learning)